<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on Canada and Alaska Dream</title>
    <link>https://canada-alaska-dream.xyz/post/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on Canada and Alaska Dream</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 13 Sep 2015 00:57:09 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://canada-alaska-dream.xyz/post/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Hello Eastern Canada - Quebec to Toronto</title>
      <link>https://canada-alaska-dream.xyz/post/hello-eastern-canada-quebec-to-toronto/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 13 Sep 2015 00:57:09 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://canada-alaska-dream.xyz/post/hello-eastern-canada-quebec-to-toronto/</guid>
      <description>Today we regretfully left Quebec behind and headed for Toronto. We had all loved our time in Quebec and I wished it had been longer.
We flew from Quebec to Toronto - landing at Billy Bishop Airport which is on a little island off mainland Toronto. A tunnel has been built underwater from Billy Bishop over to Toronto proper and is a very short, less than 10 minute walk, even lugging luggage (again - that must be how it got its name).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hello Eastern Canada - Montreal to Quebec</title>
      <link>https://canada-alaska-dream.xyz/post/hello-eastern-canada-montreal-to-quebec/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 12 Sep 2015 23:27:30 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://canada-alaska-dream.xyz/post/hello-eastern-canada-montreal-to-quebec/</guid>
      <description>Caught the train from Montreal to Quebec. Three hour trip but Liz and I occupied ourselves by studying the back of our eyelids and left Mark to read in peace.
After arriving in Quebec, we got a cab and went to the address given by our Air BnB host. I could tell by the driver&amp;rsquo;s surprise that he was not used to taking people from the railway station to an address in that area and he asked if we were going to stay with family.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hello Eastern Canada - Montreal (Day 2)</title>
      <link>https://canada-alaska-dream.xyz/post/hello-eastern-canada-montreal-day-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 12 Sep 2015 23:24:29 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://canada-alaska-dream.xyz/post/hello-eastern-canada-montreal-day-2/</guid>
      <description>Getting an early start on these holidays has been perhaps the hardest thing to do, so we were quite excited to be able to leave the accommodation early - well for us.
With Mark leading the way, we caught a train to the hop on, hop off bus and made our first stop down near the wharf and close to Old Montreal. We walked around the streets for a while, really enjoying the architecture of past decades/centuries.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hello Eastern Canada - Montreal (Day 1)</title>
      <link>https://canada-alaska-dream.xyz/post/hello-eastern-canada-montreal/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 12 Sep 2015 23:04:55 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://canada-alaska-dream.xyz/post/hello-eastern-canada-montreal/</guid>
      <description>We made it to Montreal and following instructions from our Air BnB host, we got a taxi to the accommodation. It was in a huge complex of apartments - mostly stayed in by students. There was a pool on the roof top and the apartment was quite nice. A bedroom each and very comfy beds. Ken, the owner&amp;rsquo;s son, was very nice but could have maybe been a bit more helpful about getting around.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hello Canada (Goodby West Canada) - Banff to Calgary</title>
      <link>https://canada-alaska-dream.xyz/post/hello-canada-banff-to-calgary/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 Sep 2015 18:30:27 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://canada-alaska-dream.xyz/post/hello-canada-banff-to-calgary/</guid>
      <description>Today, we would leave Banff, go to Calgary and take a plane to the eastern side of Canada to visit Montreal, Quebec, Toronto, Thousand Islands and Niagara Falls.
After a much earlier start than we liked or were very familiar with while on this trip, we said goodbye to the travelling 7 and became the travelling 4 and travelling 3. It was sad to say goodbye to our companions and it was with heavy hearts that we pulled out of the Canmore Worldmark accommodation for our trip to Calgary Airport.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hello Canada Again (Jasper - Maligne Canyon)</title>
      <link>https://canada-alaska-dream.xyz/post/hello-canada-again-jasper/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 03 Sep 2015 23:41:13 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://canada-alaska-dream.xyz/post/hello-canada-again-jasper/</guid>
      <description>After a lot of work done by Mark in planning out prospective sights to see and places to go, we decided to use the 7-seater Dodge Caravan and all travel together for the day. We went to Maligne Canyon (apparently pronounced Maleen). What a fantastic place - full of waterfalls, dramatic canyon walls, running water, rapids and a number of &amp;ldquo;bridges&amp;rdquo; for you to walk to. Swirling, churning water has worn the canyon, only two metres across at some points, to a depth of more than 50 metres There are four bridges across the gorge, each with its own special view.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hello Canada Again (Kamloops to Jasper)</title>
      <link>https://canada-alaska-dream.xyz/post/hello-canada-again-kamloops-to-jasper/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 03 Sep 2015 23:04:41 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://canada-alaska-dream.xyz/post/hello-canada-again-kamloops-to-jasper/</guid>
      <description>After a night resting and recovering from our journey the previous day, we had a fairly late start to our journey to Jasper, which is in Alberta. Our trip from Vancouver to Kamloops had been done through British Columbia. British Columbia&amp;rsquo;s scenery had been amazing, so Alberta had a lot to live up to.
On the way, we decided to go through Clearwater and visit the Spahats Falls. There are a lot of waterfalls in Canada, and believe me, visiting them NEVER gets old.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Vancouver to Kamloops (Part 2)</title>
      <link>https://canada-alaska-dream.xyz/post/vancouver-to-kamloops-part-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 03 Sep 2015 22:51:05 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://canada-alaska-dream.xyz/post/vancouver-to-kamloops-part-2/</guid>
      <description>After our quick, but exhilarating trip to Hell&amp;rsquo;s Gate, we piled back into the car, content that we had done all we wanted to, and continued to Kamloops.
I don&amp;rsquo;t think I mentioned in the Part 1 blog that once we had left Vancouver proper and gotten clear of its outlying suburbs, the scenery was amazing. Canada is so beautiful. It has not disappointed at all. Nearly every bend or turn in the road brought another breathtaking vista of snow-capped mountains, trees, trees and more trees (I love trees, I have discovered - especially the ones over here) - Douglas Fir trees, Silver Birch, evergreens - Christmas tree heaven!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hello Canada Again (Vancouver - Kamloops) Part 1</title>
      <link>https://canada-alaska-dream.xyz/post/hello-canada-again-vancouver-kamloops/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Sep 2015 23:12:20 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://canada-alaska-dream.xyz/post/hello-canada-again-vancouver-kamloops/</guid>
      <description>After a night&amp;rsquo;s sleep in Vancouver, it was time to hit the open road in our rented cars to head to Kamloops - the first stop on our Rockies journey. The plane flight from Anchorage to Vancouver the previous night had been delayed and delayed. Apparently they were waiting for the cabin crew to arrive from Spokane. Eventually they advised that the plane from Spokane containing our crew had arrived but they couldn&amp;rsquo;t taxi into their parking spot because there was another plane in that spot waiting for THEIR crew.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hello Alaska (Talkeetna - Anchorage)</title>
      <link>https://canada-alaska-dream.xyz/post/hello-alaska-talkeetna-anchorage/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Aug 2015 21:43:06 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://canada-alaska-dream.xyz/post/hello-alaska-talkeetna-anchorage/</guid>
      <description>Unfortunately today we had to leave Talkeetna. We were returning to Anchorage by bus and our lovely new friend, Alicia, ferried us in two loads up to the Alaskan Lodge where the bus would leave from.
The bus ride back was uneventful, but beautiful scenery. Liz enjoyed the bus ride much more than the train. Maybe it was because those women couldn&amp;rsquo;t play cards on the bus and keep her awake?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hello Alaska (Talkeetna - Full Day 2)</title>
      <link>https://canada-alaska-dream.xyz/post/hello-alaska-talkeetna-full-day-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Aug 2015 21:37:35 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://canada-alaska-dream.xyz/post/hello-alaska-talkeetna-full-day-2/</guid>
      <description>After another good night&amp;rsquo;s sleep, except perhaps for Helen, who is not very well at the moment, most of us had a leisurely start to the day. Liz and Mark were off to do ziplining and the rest of us were just content to enjoy our surroundings and have a bit of a rest day before we start travelling again tomorrow.
Liz and Mark returned in time for lunch at the local cafe - Latitude 62 (because this is the latitude Talkeetna is situated at), and which is just 2 minutes up the road.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hello Alaska (Talkeetna - Full Day 1)</title>
      <link>https://canada-alaska-dream.xyz/post/hello-alaska-talkeetna-full-day-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Aug 2015 21:21:48 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://canada-alaska-dream.xyz/post/hello-alaska-talkeetna-full-day-1/</guid>
      <description>Five of the spokes decided that their activity for the day would be an ATV adventure, so Wayne, Bernie, Don, Helen and Mark headed out in a procession behind Dennis (the owner of the tour) for a trip through the countryside and a visit to his home and some gold panning in the stream that runs through his property.
Liz and I had been unsure of our ability to handle the ATV, so elected to take a 3-river jet boat tour of the Chulitna, Susitna and Talkeetna Rivers.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hello Alaska (Anchorage to Talkeetna)</title>
      <link>https://canada-alaska-dream.xyz/post/hello-alaska-anchorage-to-talkeetna/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Aug 2015 20:44:01 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://canada-alaska-dream.xyz/post/hello-alaska-anchorage-to-talkeetna/</guid>
      <description>After a great night&amp;rsquo;s sleep in the Ramada Anchorage&amp;rsquo;s very comfy beds, we got a shuttle to the station for the Denali Star train to Talkeetna. (The Ramada Anchorage is no oil painting, but the comfiness of the beds and the lovely meal available at the Slippery Salmon next door, made up for that). The photo below shows the original steam train on the line.
The train trip was, I think, a little disappointing.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hello Alaska (Seward to Anchorage)</title>
      <link>https://canada-alaska-dream.xyz/post/hello-alaska-seward-to-anchorage/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Aug 2015 18:47:25 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://canada-alaska-dream.xyz/post/hello-alaska-seward-to-anchorage/</guid>
      <description>Today we disembarked the ship (a very quick, easy procedure) and got our bus for the journey to Anchorage. We opted for an all-day bus trip that took in the scenery, sights and allowed for photo stops along the way, along with a visit to Exit Glacier and the Alaskan Wildlife Conservation Centre. Another glacier I hear you ask???? Yes, another glacier, but just as spectacular as the others we had seen.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My view on the Norwegian Sun</title>
      <link>https://canada-alaska-dream.xyz/post/my-view-on-the-norwegian-sun/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Aug 2015 18:18:12 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://canada-alaska-dream.xyz/post/my-view-on-the-norwegian-sun/</guid>
      <description>I am afraid that I am a &amp;ldquo;review&amp;rdquo; reader and had read a lot of reviews on the Norwegian Sun cruises, specifically the Alaskan ones. There were a number of reviews that complained about the food, the &amp;ldquo;outdatedness&amp;rdquo; (another word I just made up) of the ship and other things. I admit I was a bit cautious about what sort of time we would have and as we all love to eat, was especially worried about those bad reviews.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hello Alaska (Norwegian Sun - Glacier Bay &amp; Hubbard Glacier)</title>
      <link>https://canada-alaska-dream.xyz/post/hello-alaska-norwegian-sun-glacier-bay/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Aug 2015 18:07:09 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://canada-alaska-dream.xyz/post/hello-alaska-norwegian-sun-glacier-bay/</guid>
      <description>We do not get off the ship any more, but today the ship sailed into Glacier Bay. We saw a couple of minor glaciers, but the cream of the crop was Margerie Glacier. I have said it before, but I think that glaciers are one of nature&amp;rsquo;s most wonderful creations. The noise they make as they calve (drop pieces of the glacier off into the water) is amazing, as is the sight of big pieces of ice falling into the water.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hello Alaska (Norwegian Sun - Skagway)</title>
      <link>https://canada-alaska-dream.xyz/post/hello-alaska-norwegian-sun-skagway/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Aug 2015 17:57:41 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://canada-alaska-dream.xyz/post/hello-alaska-norwegian-sun-skagway/</guid>
      <description>After another lovely night&amp;rsquo;s sleep, we arrived in Skagway. This was my pick of the three places visited by the Norwegian Sun. So quaint, so lovely, so old fashioned. The sidewalks were boardwalks and the shopfronts really gave it that old time &amp;ldquo;town in the wilderness&amp;rdquo; feel.
The tour I was on did not leave until nearly midday, so I spent a good deal of time walking around the town, which was a very easy walk.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hello Alaska (Norwegian Sun - Juneau)</title>
      <link>https://canada-alaska-dream.xyz/post/hello-alaska-norwegian-sun-juneau/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Aug 2015 17:43:35 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://canada-alaska-dream.xyz/post/hello-alaska-norwegian-sun-juneau/</guid>
      <description>It has been a while since I blogged, so hopefully I won&amp;rsquo;t forget too much that has happened. I do have Old Timer&amp;rsquo;s you know.
Juneau was, in my eyes anyway, not as quaint and lovely as Ketchikan - a bit more upmarket. As it is the capital of Alaska, I guess that is why. Helen, Don and I did a Mendenhall Glacier and Whale Watching tour together. Once again, the weather blessed us.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hello Alaska (Norwegian Sun - Ketchikan)</title>
      <link>https://canada-alaska-dream.xyz/post/hello-alaska-ketchikan/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Aug 2015 21:22:36 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://canada-alaska-dream.xyz/post/hello-alaska-ketchikan/</guid>
      <description>Just a quick blog today. We are all sharing internet time bought by the Mitchells and the rest of us will give them money towards their cost.
Boarded the Norwegian Sun on Monday 17 August 2015 (Vancouver time). Boarding was very efficient. Of course when you are boarding all those passengers you are undoubtedly going to have to stand in queues, but these were all managed very well - all under cover and sheltered from the weather.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hello Canada (Vancouver - Day 3)</title>
      <link>https://canada-alaska-dream.xyz/post/hello-canada-vancouver-day-3/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 16 Aug 2015 22:54:22 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://canada-alaska-dream.xyz/post/hello-canada-vancouver-day-3/</guid>
      <description>What a great day the travellers had in Vancouver today. Catching the free shuttle bus, we went to the Capilano Suspension Bridge Park and as the name suggests, there is a suspension bridge. It is quite a long one and moves a lot because there is usually a lot of people on it. With the hub&amp;rsquo;s insight (obtained from reading reviews on Trip Advisor), the travellers went early when it wasn&amp;rsquo;t quite as busy.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hello Canada - (Vancouver - Day 2)</title>
      <link>https://canada-alaska-dream.xyz/post/hello-canada-vancouver-day-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 16 Aug 2015 00:55:16 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://canada-alaska-dream.xyz/post/hello-canada-vancouver-day-2/</guid>
      <description>Day 2 in Vancouver started slowly for the hub. Bit of a lie-in, then downstairs late morning where the doorman talked me out of going anywhere until after midday due to a half marathon being held and road closures relating to that. So, after midday I went down and waited for a hop-on, hop-off bus to Stanley Park. This park is 150 acres larger than New York&amp;rsquo;s Central Park. After about 50 minutes, decided there might be some problems with the hop-on, hop-off bus, so got a taxi to the Park.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hello Canada (Goodbye Whistler ... Vancouver - Day 1)</title>
      <link>https://canada-alaska-dream.xyz/post/hello-canada-vancouver-day-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 15 Aug 2015 00:32:19 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://canada-alaska-dream.xyz/post/hello-canada-vancouver-day-1/</guid>
      <description>This afternoon we left beautiful Whistler for Vancouver. Our limo (yes, another one) wasn&amp;rsquo;t picking us up until 1.00pm, for Helen and I took a walk to Lost Lake. They have to change the name now because we found it. Although Helen and some of the others had found it on our first day in Whistler, it really only mattered when the hub found it. It was about 50 minutes to get there (could scout Helen have perhaps taken me the wrong [sorry, a different] way?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hello Canada (Whistler - Day 2)</title>
      <link>https://canada-alaska-dream.xyz/post/hello-canada-whistler-day-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Aug 2015 00:55:14 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://canada-alaska-dream.xyz/post/hello-canada-whistler-day-2/</guid>
      <description>What an action packed day it was for the travellers in Whistler today (15 August 2015). After a leisurely breakfast, the six spokes and the hub tagging along for beautification purposes, went to the Olympic Sliding Centre (yes THE Olympic Sliding Centre used in the 2010 Olympic Winter Games) to do some bobsledding. In summer they put wheels on the bobsleds and run them down the actual Olympic track, although you don&amp;rsquo;t start until the 7th gate, so not right from the very top.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hello Canada (Whistler - Day 1)</title>
      <link>https://canada-alaska-dream.xyz/post/hello-canada-whistler/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Aug 2015 00:00:17 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://canada-alaska-dream.xyz/post/hello-canada-whistler/</guid>
      <description>Thanks to Spoke Wayne&amp;rsquo;s beautiful organising we were picked up from our Victoria Worldmark accommodation and whisked away in a black Mercedes Sprinter (10 seater) to another ferry for the trip across to mainland Canada. Huge ferry &amp;hellip; three decks of cars and semis and buses and decks with eating facilities, lounges etc. Approx 90-minute trip and we continued in our Mercedes Sprinter through to Whistler. This was a good couple of hours stretch, through the city of Vancouver and on.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hello Canada (Victoria)</title>
      <link>https://canada-alaska-dream.xyz/post/hello-canada-victoria/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Aug 2015 23:51:32 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://canada-alaska-dream.xyz/post/hello-canada-victoria/</guid>
      <description>On the morning of 11 August (Canadian time) we caught a ferry from Seattle to Vancouver Island (Victoria) and finally after 45 years of dreaming on my part, myself and the six spokes arrived in Canada. I was so excited (as was everyone). Checked into our accommodation at Worldmark Kingston and went to Fisherman&amp;rsquo;s Wharf for a lunch of fish and chips.
Once I get the code worked out for inserting photos you will be able to see some of the beautiful things I have seen &amp;hellip;by George I think I&amp;rsquo;ve got it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Things I have learned</title>
      <link>https://canada-alaska-dream.xyz/post/things-i-have-learned/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Aug 2015 22:06:10 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://canada-alaska-dream.xyz/post/things-i-have-learned/</guid>
      <description>The water in the toilet DOES flush the other way; light and power switches operate the opposite way; Americans/Canadians are very polite, when going up and down stairs - walk on the opposite side to home and so far, most importantly, when crossing a road, look to the LEFT first, the LEFT &amp;hellip; always the LEFT first.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hello Seattle!</title>
      <link>https://canada-alaska-dream.xyz/post/hello-seattle/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Aug 2015 01:03:20 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://canada-alaska-dream.xyz/post/hello-seattle/</guid>
      <description>Okay &amp;hellip; arrived safely after loooong plane flight. Managed to contain myself and did not ask &amp;ldquo;Are we there yet&amp;rdquo; once. Was actually lucky to get to Seattle as I answered a question at the airport with &amp;ldquo;Yes&amp;rdquo;. The question was &amp;ldquo;Is anyone going to Vila?&amp;rdquo;
Staying at a Worldmark hotel &amp;hellip; The Camlin &amp;hellip; In Seattle. Rooms are lovely and very comfy. First day sightseeing and what a day. Beautiful weather.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>3 Days To Go: To Pack Or Not To Pack</title>
      <link>https://canada-alaska-dream.xyz/post/3-days-to-go-to-pack-or-not-to-pack/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Aug 2015 01:01:23 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://canada-alaska-dream.xyz/post/3-days-to-go-to-pack-or-not-to-pack/</guid>
      <description>Well, 3 sleeps to go and I have finally decided to do something about packing. I am one of those people who don&amp;rsquo;t like to have everything done and dusted well before time because it seems to make things go faster if I wait. So I waited and now am slightly panicked.
What on earth do I take? Going to Canada and Alaska, admittedly in the last month of their summer, I would think that basically pants/t-shirts and one, maybe two, good outfits would do, with a jumper.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>I am starting this blog to detail my trip of a lifetime to Canada and Alaska.</title>
      <link>https://canada-alaska-dream.xyz/post/i-am-starting-this-blog-to-detail-my-trip-of-a-lifetime-to-canada-and-alaska/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Jul 2015 21:14:30 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://canada-alaska-dream.xyz/post/i-am-starting-this-blog-to-detail-my-trip-of-a-lifetime-to-canada-and-alaska/</guid>
      <description>For me this trip has been 45 years in the making. I started dreaming about it when just a teenager and finally, at the age of 60, will leave on 8 August 2015. I am taking the trip with 6 friends - all couples. Some might say I am the seventh wheel, but I prefer to think of it as being the central hub and the others as the spokes that revolve around me!</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>